# **Grant Kopplin**

P: 918-606-2738 grant.kopplin@gmail.com LinkedIn Github

## **ABOUT ME**

I am a full-stack software developer specializing in solving complex data management problems and building beautiful, functional frontend applications. Through working for a non-profit research institute for three years, I learned how to tackle complex data puzzles and further developed my passion for the broader social impact of the work that I do. I excel at picking up new skills quickly and I am driven to constantly grow and look for ways to improve my projects with cutting-edge technologies.

SKILLS Java, JavaScript, Spring, React, Redux, Ruby, Rails, SQL, AWS, Docker, Jenkins, ELK, Git, Swift, Xcode

# **PROJECTS**

**Grumblr** | (React/Redux, Rails, Webpack, AWS, postgreSQL, HTML/CSS, Heroku)

live | github

• Designed and created a full-stack clone of Tumblr for people who love to grumble, and integrated AWS S3 cloud storage with the Rails backend to reduce local data storage and improve scalability.

Java Developer Course Capstone Project | (Spring Boot, SQL, Docker, RabbitMQ, Jenkins, ELK)

github

 Designed and created a Reddit-like Spring Boot API with Dockerized microservices, CI/CD and monitoring, and inter-service communication via a messaging queue.

Maze Escape | (JavaScript, HTML5 Canvas, CSS)

live | github

 Designed and created a retro, turn-based maze escape game with AI enemies, and implemented logic to conditionally show/hide HTML elements (such as instructions and the win screen) based on the user's progression through the levels of the game.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Volunteer Software Developer**

North Brooklyn DSA

June 2019 - Present

- Setting up authentication for an iOS canvassing app for political campaigns and sending HTTP requests to an external API containing data on voters.
- Implementing functionality to monitor network connectivity changes using the Reachability.swift library and update Views Controllers accordingly.

#### **Research Assistant**

Guttmacher Institute Dec 20

Dec 2015 - Feb 2019

- Standardized Stata datasets for 147 countries for the latest iteration of *Adding It Up*, a heavily cited series summarizing global contraceptive use and maternal/newborn health.
- Created a system for pulling and processing data from PDFs using Tabula, which greatly improved efficiency and minimized errors compared to manual data entry.

#### **EDUCATION**

**General Assembly** - 2019 - Cognizant-sponsored Java Developer course **App Academy** - 2019 - A highly selective, full-stack web development course **Yale University** - BS Psychology, 2010-2015